Mega Evolution:
A new form of Pokémon evolution that has spread through the Kalos region.
People, I ask you:
Is Mega Evolution possibly a means to test Pokémon and people?
Can Mega Evolution happen to all Pokémon?
Apart from the fact that it unleashes Pokémon's hidden powers,
changing their appearance to make them look much stronger and braver,
we still don't know that much about it.
The Strongest Mega Evolution
At the end of the show, we have an exquisite present quiz! Prepare to take notes!
A Mega Stone.
Show me your strongest.
You're quite confident, huh? I hope you're not just all bark and no bite.
While watching anime, make sure not to sit too close to the screen and that the room is well lit.
What's your name?
Alan.
I'm Ayaka.
And this little one is my strongest partner.
Come on out, Absol!
It is present.
Roar, Lizardon! Flamethrower!
Absol, Psycho Cut!
Megahorn!
Grab its horn!
Play a board game via the Pocket Monsters XY data broadcast!
Press the d-button on your remote and try reaching the battles and the presents!!
Its power is impressive.
But this can't be the end of it.
Let's get serious, shall we?
Heh. I'll show you.
Absol, mega evolve!
What do you think of Mega Absol?
I've never seen the Mega Evolution of Absol before.
Show me you're serious as well.
Respond to my heart,
Key Stone!
Surpass evolution!
Mega evolve!
My strongest: Mega Lizardon.
That black body looks quite cool.
I'm honored to be praised by you.
Let's go! Steel Wing!
Counter with Megahorn!
What?
What's the matter?
Huh, what?
What kind of Pokémon are those?
Is that an alternate colored Lizardon? But it seems different from an ordinary Lizardon...
And that Absol has wings. I don't get it.
Dragon Claw!
Dodge!
I can't believe the power it has...
Flamethrower!
Amazing...
Good job enduring that, Absol.
Dark Pulse!
Blast Burn!
Absol!
Absol...
That was excellent, Lizardon.
Lizardon and Absol transformed?
You fought well, Absol.
Let's battle again someday.
Are you always like this?
Battling only for the sake of becoming the strongest?
Together with this Lizardon, I want to defeat all Mega Evolutions...
...and stand at the top!
Mega Absol put up quite a bit of a fight.
It was well raised.
Why don't you stop hiding and just come out?
Hi!
Anything you want?
Uhm, that's...
I watched the battle earlier and was shocked when I saw that black Lizardon, so...
What was that? Not a new Pokémon, was it?
You want to battle us?
Non, non! Impossible, impossible!
We only just set off a while ago, so there's no way we could battle like that!
Seems like a beginner, Lizardon.
I'm Manon.
This little one is Hari-san the Harimaron.
I got it at Professor Platane's place just recently.
Oh, right! I'll tell you a nice story!
There's an amazing Trainer that Professor Platane told me about!
Some time ago, the Gablias at the laboratory went on a rampage, you know.
Gablias...
You didn't know? It was a huge incident!
And see, Satoshi, the Trainer who helped Gablias, he was really amazing!
When a Pokémon fell from the top of Miare's Prism Tower, he jumped right after it!
You can't do that unless you trust each other, right?
Huh?
Nothing.
Mister, what's your name?
Alan.
Right now, I'm traveling with this guy to master Mega Evolution.
Hey, hey, does Mega Evolution mean evolution?
Do you possibly mean the black Lizardon from earlier, by any chance?
Uh... Yeah.
It was Mega Lizardon.
That's amazing! I didn't know there's an evolution like that!
Hari-san, you were shocked too, right?
Hey, can Hari-san become like that, too?
Who knows?
It's not like I know everything about Mega Evolution.
Two stones seem to have a strong connection to Mega Evolution.
Two stones?
One is held by the Trainer and the other by the Pokémon.
When the two stones resonate, the Pokémon temporarily attains great power.
But where does that power come from?
Is it given to them by humans?
No, it's the Pokémon's own power.
Humans only draw out the power using the stone, that's all.
I think it is the strong bond between human and Pokémon which allows this phenomenon to happen.
A bond, huh...?
Does Mega Evolution only come to existence through humans?
Yes.
That said, there are still many mysteries.
It was an established theory that Pokémon can't turn back to their previous forms once they evolve.
However, Mega Evolution overthrows that theory. They return back to normal.
Another question is why it only occurs during battles.
According to the information in our possession, there are cases of Pokémon changing their types and Abilities upon mega evolving.
If their typing and Abilities change,
releasing the power might place a burden on the Pokémon.
Is that why it only happens during a battle?
That's a possibility.
Either way, we don't have enough samples.
You're right.
I wonder how things are in other regions.
So far, all reported cases happened here in the Kalos region.
There, there.
The Pokémon might be trying to tell us something through Mega Evolution.
That's exactly the topic of my research.
As someone researching Pokémon in Kalos, it's something I don't think I can avoid looking into.
I'll look for stones!
Do you want to set off on a journey?
It's okay, right, Professor?
Uh... Yeah.
But report to me on a regular basis.
I will!
What's wrong? You're so absent-minded.
I was thinking back.
To what?
Professor Platane.
Huh?
I used to be the professor's assistant.
Really? But why are you traveling if you're the professor's assistant?
About that...
Huh? Why? Why?
None of your business.
It's me, Alan.
This is your next destination.
Got it.
Alan?
Return, Lizardon.
Wait! I still have some questions...
What now, Hari-san?
I know, right? You want to know, too, right?
All right, let's go!
Sorry for bothering you.
The Strongest Mega Evolution ~Act I~
Excellence! VS Mega Gablias!!
This program is brought to you by these sponsors.
Zumi of the Elite Four has a Mega Kamex!?
The exquisite present quiz is soon! Prepare to take notes!
Huh?
Where has he gone?
I found it...
There's no mistake.
Maybe he's in here?
Alan, found you!
You're still there?
Were you looking for something?
Something related to Mega Evolution?
You're pesky.
Wait a second!
That's a Mega Stone, right?
I was told to bring that as well.
Hide over there.
Okay.
Why don't we battle over that Mega Stone?
And if I say no?
Don't be so cold.
My partner, Gabunoji!
A Gablias...
A battle between two who can mega evolve.
I've got a Key Stone, too!
Oh, looks like you're getting motivated.
Come out, Lizardon!
Let's mega evolve right away, then.
That's the spirit!
I'm the great Dragon Trainer Louis. My Gabunoji is quite impressive.
My partner is a Dragon too, after all.
Wha? What kind of amateur are you? Lizardon's not a Dragon.
Who's the amateur here?
Very well.
Time to battle, Lizardon! Release your power and mega evolve!
We won't hold back either! Open your eyes and take a good look!
Gabunoji, mega evolve!
I can feel they're radiating with power...
Dragon Rush!
It hit.
What?!
Flamethrower!
All right! There's more!
Dual Chop!
Dragon Claw!
Gabunoji...
Well done.
Remember this.
When this guy mega evolves, it becomes a Fire/Dragon type.
Amazing... He won again.
Don't follow me.
I can do whatever I want!
Alan, you may seem a little scary and all, but you're super-nice to Lizardon!
I think you do love Pokémon after all, you're definitely not a bad person,
and you have a big dream like becoming the strongest Mega Evolution user, so you're kind of my ideal type!
Do you want to praise me or diss me? Make up your mind.
Besides, I want to mega evolve.
I want to get more and more Pokémon, raise them to become strong and then win against you and Lizardon.
Is that so?
What's with that tone?
It's a Flabebe! Hari-san, let's get it!
There it is! Pin Missile!
Vine Whip!
Geez, how nimble you are!
Why isn't it landing hits?
You're struggling.
Don't you have moves that could poison or confuse it?
I do...
Use them. They'll slow its movement.
Got it. Hari-san, Toxic!
Amazing, it's working!
Don't get distracted. Throw a ball.
Yeah!
Please, monster ball!
All right! I got my first wild Pokémon!
That's great. Hurry up and treat that poisoning.
Oh, right.
Here, Flabebe has fully recovered.
Thank you, Joy-san, Pukurin!
Fla-chan, please bear with me from now on!
Oh, right. Do you know where the Trainer I was with is now?
He already left.
What?
When I told him that Zumi-san of the Elite Four has a restaurant nearby...
Zumi-sama of the Elite Four, you say?!
Hurry, Hari-san!
Welcome. My name is Zumi.
I want to try your unofficial menu.
Understood. However, it is anything but gentle on the taste buds.
I actually prefer that.
Hey, hey! Don't leave me behind!
Who is this?
I'm his travel companion!
Whoa, it's you in the flesh!?
Now then, young lady, you can come with us.
I wonder if Zumi-san's Pokémon mega evolves, too.
Excuse me, but you're using a Fire type against me, a Water type Trainer?
Yeah, I know. But I want to be the strongest together with Lizardon.
Regardless of type and compatibility, the bond between us will overcome reason!
Respond to my heart,
Key Stone!
Surpass evolution!
Mega evolve!
It is promising to see it devote its body and soul to the Pokémon battle...
It's truly an art.
I'd like to see you surpass me.
Show me the full power of an Elite Four member.
Dragon Claw!
Let's start with the hors d'oeuvre.
Rapid-fire Hydro Pump!
Skull Bash!
Whoa, they both have amazing power!
Its speed and power are exquisite. What an excellent texture.
It's time for the main dish to get served.
You're right.
Let me offer you a taste...
of my artistic main dish!
Kamex, mega evolve!
As I thought, it mega evolved!
Steel Wing!
Dragon Pulse!
Mega Kamex's Ability is Mega Launcher.
The power of Pulse moves increases compared to when it was a Kamex.
Could you taste it?
Moreover, we shall let you experience the water power of a Mega Evolution.
Hydro Pump!
Charge!
Power-Up Punch!
Flamethrower!
It's not like Fire has no effect at all.
Dragon Claw!
It's been a while since I last had fresh meat with a backbone.
But I shall finish it with this.
Dragon Pulse!
The match is over, it seems.
Zumi-san is too strong...
Lizardon, thanks for the hard work.
We're no match for the Elite Four, huh?
They were powerful enough to corner us even with us a type disadvantage...
That was excellent.
Wait, Alan!
The exquisite present quiz will be right after this! Prepare to take notes!
Give it a rest already.
Non, non! I will definitely mega evolve, too!
The one evolving won't be you, but your Pokémon.
I know that! I'll search for those stones too.
If I'm with you, I'll find some for sure, right?
Do as you please.
Uh, hey!
The number of Pokémon able to mega evolve increase more and more.
Unknown Mega Evolutions, awaken!
And fill this world with powerful might!
How will this great power called Mega Evolution...
...influence humans and Pokémon?
We're living in changing times.
Alan, let's solve the mystery of Mega Evolution!